## David Sagasti, MBA

Bangkok, Thailand 0954649147 david.sagasti@gmail.com



## Achievements

Experienced muti-discipline professional with over 20 years of experience in business development, key account management, audit, customer relationship management, and marketing communications.

- During my 10-year tenure at IBM, I held roles as multi-country sales support manager, business analyst, and corporate
  auditor conducting audits in over 20 countries. Having resided in various countries, including Spain, the UK,
  Hungary, Laos, and currently Bangkok for the past 5 years, I bring a global perspective to my work.
- My credentials include an Executive MBA from the Central European University, which equipped me with a strong foundation in strategic management and leadership.
- In 2018, I ventured into the Asian market, working for European companies on international governmental
  cooperation and business development. Now, I am eager to leverage my expertise and welcome new opportunities for
  professional growth.

## **Education**

#### MBA, Central European/New York University, December 2013, Budapest (Hungary)

AMBA-accredited MBA degree granted by New York State's Department of Education, strong focus on Ethical Leadership and Emerging Markets.

#### Business Studies, University of the West of England, September 2004, Bristol (UK)

Completed modules in Financial Information, Business Information Technology Management, and Management and Organisational Behaviour.

#### **Professional experience**

## Founder/Managing Director, April 2021 to date - Eurasian Solutions, Bangkok

Thai registered company providing business consultancy, acting as a bridge to Southeast Asia for European companies specialized in Digital and Industry Transformation.

https://www.eurasian.solutions

# Business Development in Asia Pacific, January 2021 to September 2022 Consulthink Solutions, Bangkok

Partner, Business Development. Pursue and develop opportunities for international cooperation in the region, providing key account management services in

- smart agricultural solutions
- water management
- digital health
- e-government

# Business Development/Key Account Manager, SE Asia, December 2018 to date R&R Software, Hungary/Laos/Thailand

Country manager on a \$25M government international cooperation project

- Relationship oversight with the key stakeholders at governmental level
- $\bullet$  Managed local office and staff, account balances, budget control and all expenses
- Produced comprehensive managerial reports of the country political situation and project status
- Pursue and develop opportunities for international cooperation in the region

#### **IBM**

## Corporate Auditor, Operations Management, and Business Analyst, 2007 to 2018, Budapest, Hungary

Joined IBM in 2007 and progressed in the following areas:

**Corporate Auditor**, from September 2015 to September 2018, Europe, Africa, Middle East, Asia, Central and South America.

- Attended relevant audit training in New York, US
- Participated in more than 30 audit engagements in 20 countries, to provide independent assessments of IBM's system of internal controls
- Audited several business areas:
  - Procurement
  - o HR processes
  - o Business Partners management
  - Asset management
  - o Complete country reviews (all processes and functions)
- Acted as Audit team leader in engagements and teams in South Africa, Israel, Korea, Kenya, and Hungary

## Client Financing Business Support Operations Manager, October 2012 - March 2015, Budapest

Manager of the sales support function for Spain, Portugal, and Israel:

Led a multicultural team of 20+ people, controlling all HR aspects

Liaise between local sales teams, accounting, F&P, and end customers, ensuring sales targets met, appropriate revenue recognition, whilst adhering to all relevant controls, compliance and regulations.

#### Corporate Service Corps 2011, Cebu City, Philippines

Participated on IBM's Corporate Social Responsibility program, consulting for the Philippines' government.

Was assigned to consult and coach a local talent NGO, drastically improving their operational efficiency

## Client Financing Business Support Operations, June 2007 – March 2011, Budapest

Complex Deal Coordinator in several internal projects across various IBM functions.

Participated in several process improvement projects

#### AXA UK

# Investment Marketing Communications - September 2005 to December 2006, Bristol, UK

- Assisted in running marketing campaigns
- Responsible for investor communications, quarterly marketing, and results materials

# Volunteer experience

# January 2011 - June 2011 IBM's Corporate Service, Cebu City, Philippines

Participated on IBM's 4-month Corporate Service Corps consulting for a local foundation, Cebu Educational Development Foundation for Information Technology, CEDF-IT. The program is designed on a 3 directional benefit- country, IBM and to develop the participant as a global leader.

#### January 1997 - May 1998 Red Cross, Tenerife, Spain

1 year of social services, after completing training on first aid and internal operations, serving as a radio operator, ambulance paramedic and sea rescue lifeguard.

## Languages

- English: Fluent (Cambridge EFL Proficiency UK, 2000, ITOEFL 637/700), UK resident for 8 years.
- Spanish: Mother tongue.

#### **Additional information**

Spanish nationality, British resident from 1999, Hungarian resident from 2005, permanent Thai resident since 2018